We're going to be talking about court position.
In tennis the ball has to go first over the net, which is your first challenge and second the ball has to land in the court.
Basically, in the court would be the dark area of the court, the dark green inside the white lines.
Outside would be everything else.
Depending what we're doing, like if we're doing a serve, we're playing singles or doubles we're going to have different lines that we're going to be talking about.
The main line is the base line as the name says.
I'm standing on it right now.
You want to stay on the center of the court which is where the small T is.
You basically want to recover the center of the court after you hit every shot.
Then you have your service line.
That is where Tracy is standing.
She is standing on the right side of the court.
The other side is going to be the left side of the court.
Then we have single lines.
Single lines is when you’re playing one person against another person, the ball has to go inside this area and then inside the base line all the way to the second single court, single line.
Then we have double lines, which are the ones that Tracy is pointing on the right side of the area and then it's going to all the way up to the base line and then it's going to go until the end of the white line.
Double lines are used when four people are playing; two against two on each side.
This is basically what the court boundaries are about.